Seymour Martin Lipset Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
- Writings, 1824-2013 (Box 55-126)
  - Books (Box 89)
    - Paradox of American Unionism: Why Americans Like Unions More Than Canadians Do, But Join Much Less, with Rafael Gomez, Ivan Katchanovski, and Noah M. Meltz (Box 113)
      - Related material (Box 117)
        - White-collar workers, 1999-2000, (3 folders) (Box 118)
      - Reviews, 2001-2003 (Box 118)
    - Party Coalitions in the 1980s, 1983-1986 (Box 118)
    - Party Systems and Voter Alignments: Cross-national Perspectives, with Stein Rokkan, 1967-1969 (Box 118)
    - Passion and Politics: Student Activism in America, with Gerald M. Schaflander, 1971-1972 (Box 118)
    - Political Man: The Social Bases of Politics, 1966-1972, 1982-1989, (2 folders) (Box 118)
    - Politics and the Social Sciences, 1969-1970 (Box 118)
    - Politics of Unreason: Right-Wing Extremism in America 1790-1970, with Earl Raab, 1969-1979, (2 folders) (Box 118)
    - Power of Jewish Education (Box 119)
      - 1990 National Jewish Population Survey, 1990-1992, (4 folders) (Box 119)
      - General, 1992-1994 (Box 119)
      - Multivariate analysis, 1991-1992, (2 folders); (3 folders) (Box 119, Box 120)
      - Printed copy, 1994 (Box 120)
    - Prejudice and Society, with Earl Raab, 1959 (Box 120)
    - Rebellion in the University: History of Student Activism in America, 1971-1977 (Box 120)
    - Revolution and Counterrevolution: Change and Persistence in Social Structures, 1968-1970, 1987-1989, (2 folders) (Box 120)
    - "Social Bases of Political Diversity in Western Democracies," with Juan J. Linz (unpublished), 1956, (2 folders); (5 folders) (Box 120, Box 121)
    - Sociology and History: Methods, with Richard Hofstadter 1968-1970 (Box 121)
    - Student Politics, 1967-1968 (Box 121)
    - Students in Revolt, with Philip G. Altbach, 1969-1970 (Box 121)
    - Third Century: America as a Post-Industrial Society, 1980-1982 (Box 121)
    - Turner and the Sociology of the Frontier, with Richard Hofstadter, 1968-1969 (Box 121)
    - Union Democracy: the Internal Politics of the International Typographical Union, with James S. Coleman and Martin A. Trow, 1969-1972 (Box 121)
    - Unions in Transition: Entering the Second Century, 1986-1987 (Box 121)
    - Who's Who in Democracy, 1996 (Box 121)
    - Unidentified chapters, 1992, undated, (2 folders) (Box 122)
  - Notebooks and notes, undated, (5 folders); (3 folders) (Box 122, Box 123)
  - Reprints for the Seymour Martin Lipset Lecture on Democracy in the World, 2008-2013, (2 folders) (Box 123)
  - Writings by others (Box 123)
    - About Lipset, 1982-1983, 1989-1993, 2002-2007 (Box 123)
    - Bell, Daniel, 1995 (Box 123)
    - Cardoso, Fernando Henrique, 1980 (Box 123)
    - Chaffee, Steven H., 1982 (Box 123)
    - Cotter, Joseph D., 1993 (Box 123)
    - Diamond, Larry Jay and Juan J. Linz, 1990-1991, (6 folders); (2 folders) (Box 124, Box 125)
    - Finifter, Ada W., 1981-1982, (5 folders) (Box 125)
    - General attacks and reviews, 1961-1981, 1990 (Box 126)
    - Hartz, Louis, 1964 (Box 126)
    - O'Connor, Sara, 1982 (Box 126)
    - Orum, Anthony M., circa 1984 (Box 126)
    - Skocpol, Theda, 1973 (Box 126)
    - Smith, Robert B., 1984 (Box 126)